Jimmy (Guo Jing) Tang

Web Developer

Work Experience

Grow Super | Front End Developer

Jan 2020 - March 2020

A team member of Grow's FrontEnd development team working on the company's flagship product; a next generation superannuation administration platform called Tina. The platform aimed to reduce the cost of administering a superfund through distributed ledger technologies and automated processes managing everything from Member Roll in and creation to earning distributions to report generation. Unfortunately due to the economic pressures of COVID-19, all staff were made redundant as of March 2020.

- Contributed code to Tina's Vue based frontend that utilised VueX, NPM and Webpack extensively throughout as well as an Express Koa based middleware.
- Spearheaded the collaborative development of Tina's Income Distribution feature working
 closely in a cross-functional team consisting Scrum Master, BA, UX and Backend despite the
 challenges of working remotely.
- Collaborated with frontend leads in code pairing sessions, code reviews and testing to improve overall code quality.
- Led a knowledge sharing session on Firebase and serverless technologies in the FrontEnd fortnightly catch ups.

Applied Technologies: Vue, Vuex, Express, Koa, Echarts, VSCode, Tailwind, Vue Test Utils

UTS Rapido | Software Developer

Dec 2015 - Dec 2019

UTS Rapido is an advanced technology development unit focused on supporting organisations to deliver hardware and software products and solutions. They specialise in bridging the gap between academic research and industry through collaborative partnerships. Whilst I worked on many projects at UTS, my crowning achievement was leading the end to end development and deployment of the Take Kare Safe Space and Incident Reporting System, an app built for the Stay Kind Foundation to help reduce alcohol related violence across Sydney's nightlife hotspots as well as improve their operational efficiencies.

- Met and consulted with end user clients to discuss design and business requirements for the
 applications that we are building for them. Structuring these requirements into features and
 implementing them in planned release cycles.
- Historical Data Migration for clients who had existing data in spreadsheets that were required in the newly developed system.
- Assist clients in understanding the data that they've collected from their applications through
 the app's built in reporting system for the purposes of improving business efficiencies and
 research outcomes.

Applied Technologies: React, Redux, Semantic UI, Firebase, Google Cloud Platform

Mint Payments | Graduate Developer

Sept 2013 - Dec 2015

The Mint Payments Mobile Point of Sale (MPOS) System is a payments system that enables Merchants to accept card payments easily through their mobile phones with the help of a mobile app and a bluetooth connected card reader. The entire system covers everything from Merchant signup and onboarding to transaction reporting to payments processing through third-party payment gateways.

- Helped develop and maintain the company's Java-based Administration and Merchant web portal that allows registered merchants to view transaction information and reports.
- Assisted in the design and development of several key RESTFUL API endpoints that provided the company's mobile app with access to transaction data, receipts, etc.
- Helped maintain the company's Merchant Onboarding Portal that was constructed out of PHP using Codelgniter framework and MySQL DB Backend.
- Helped develop and maintain the company's Continuous Integration Server, Jenkins.
 Developed UAT Environment deployment scripts as well as assisted in the migration to Atlassian Bamboo.

Applied Technologies: Spring, Java, JSP, PHP, Hibernate, MSSQL, MySQL, JQuery

+61 405 978 992 jimmy.gj.tang@gmail.com

https://jimmytang.dev/

About Me

I'm a self taught Web Developer who loves building applications with modern web technologies. Familiar with Javascript front end frameworks React and Vue that required state management with Redux and VueX.

Have had experience integrating with Express middleware and backends that exposed JWT authenticated RESTful endpoints and experimented with some GraphQL.

Currently rounding out my stack experience diving deeper into backend frameworks and database design.

Trying to focus on not chasing the next cool JS library because there's always more to learn!:)

Technologies

Languages

Javascript, HTML, CSS, SQL, Typescript

FrontEnd

React, Redux, Vue, VueX, Tailwind, SemanticUI, Echarts

BackEnd

Express, GraphQL, NestJS, Spring Boot MVC

Databases

PostgreSQL, Sequelize, MongoDB, Mongoose, TypeORM

IDEs/Source Control

IntelliJ, VSCode, Git, Git Desktop, Bitbucket

Testing

Enzyme, Vue Test Utils, Jest, Cypress.io

Cloud/Deployment

Google Firebase, Google Cloud Functions, TravisCl, Docker

Miscellaneous

Confluence, Jira, Figma, Photoshop, Lightroom

Education

Bachelor of Innovations ICT Engineering (Software/Network), Diploma in Engineering Practice University of Technology, Sydney